(
"ai_sub_version": "3.5.1",
"generated_at": "2026-08-12T12:33:02.387525",
"lyrics_prompt_version": 9,
"subtitles_prompt_version": 18,
"complete": true,
"max_retries_exceeded": false,
"any_pending": false,
"settings": (
"ai": (
"model": null,
"model_subtitles": "google-gla:gemini-3.5-flash-lite",
"model_lyrics": "google-gla:gemini-3.5-flash-lite",
"rpm": 4,
"tpm": 250000,
"google": (
"file_cache_ttl": 10,
"use_files_api": true,
"max_storage_gb": 18.0
),
"search": (
"qps": 0.3,
"max_length": 4096,
"web_search_tool": "langsearch",
"timeout": 60.0,
"retries": 3,
"min_wait_seconds": 1.0,
"max_wait_seconds": 10.0,
"multiplier": 2.0
),
"validation_buffer_ms": 2000,
"verification_gap_seconds": 60,
"gap_verification_retries": 1,
"gap_verification_ignore_start": true,
"gap_verification_ignore_end": true
),
"split": (
"max_seconds": 300,
"re_encode": (
"enabled": false,
"fps": 1.0,
"height": 360,
"bitrate_kb": 35,
"threshold_mb": 20,
"duration_tolerance_ms": 100,
"encoder": null
),
"start_offset_min": 0
"thread": (
"uploads": 4,
"re_encode": 2,
"lyrics": 4,
"subtitles": 4
),
"retry": (
"per_run": 5,
"max_runs": 3,
"multiplier": 2.0,
"min_wait_seconds": 30.0,
"max_wait_seconds": 300
),
"log": (
"level": "info",
"timestamps": true,
"scrub": false,
"progress_bars": true,
"progress_bar_width": 80,
"progress_bar_refresh_seconds": 1.0
)
世界の始まりの日
On the day the world began,
生命の樹の下で
Beneath the tree of life,
くじらたちの声の
The distant echoes of
遠い残響 二人で聞いた
the whales' voices, heard by us two.
失くしたもの すべて
Everything we lost,
愛したもの すべて
Everything we loved,
この手に抱きしめて
Clasping them in these hands,
現在は何処を
Where are we wandering
彷徨い行くの
now?
答えの潜む 琥珀の太陽
The amber sun where answers lie hidden,
出会わなければ 殺戮の天使でいられた
If we hadn't met, I could've been an angel of slaughter.
不死なる瞬き持つ魂
A soul with an immortal blink,
傷つかないで 僕の羽根
Do not be hurt, my wings.
この気持ち知るため 生まれてきた
I was born to know this feeling.
一万年と二千年前から 愛してる
I've loved you since 12,000 years ago,
八千年間過ぎた頃から もっと恋しくなった
And I fell even more in love 8,000 years since then.
一億と二千年あとも 愛してる
I will love you 100 million and 2,000 years from now.
君を知ったその日から 僕の地獄に音楽は絶えない
Since the day I met you, music never ceases in my hell.
世界が終わる前に
Before the world ends,
生命が終わる前に
Before life ends,
眠る嘆きほどいて
Untying the sleeping sighs,
君の薫り 抱きしめたいよ
I want to embrace your fragrance.
耳すませた 海神の記憶
The memories of the sea god we listened to,
失意にのまれ 立ち尽くす 麗しき月
The beautiful moon standing still in despair.
よみがえれ
Revive...
よみがえれ 永遠に涸れぬ光
Revive, eternal light that will never run dry
汚されないで 君の夢
Don't let your dream be stained
祈り宿しながら 生まれてきた
Born holding a prayer within
一万年と二千年前から 愛してる
I've loved you since 12,000 years ago
八千年過ぎた頃から もっと恋しくなった
Since 8,000 years passed, I've missed you more
一億と二千年あとも 愛してる
I still love you after 100,020,000 years
君を知ったその日から 僕の地獄に音楽は絶えない
Since the day I knew you, music has never ceased in my hell
君が繰り返し 大人になって 何度も何度も遠くへ行って
Growing up again and again, going far away over and over
見守る僕が 眠れない僕が くしゃくしゃになったとしても
Even if I, who watch over and cannot sleep, become all crumpled up
君の名を歌うために
To sing your name...
一万年と二千年前から 愛してる
I've loved you since 12,000 years ago
八千年過ぎた頃から もっと恋しくなった
Since 8,000 years passed, I've missed you more
一億と二千年あとも 愛してる
I still love you after 100,020,000 years
君を知ったその日から
Since the day I knew you...
一万年と二千年前から 愛してる
I've loved you since 12,000 years ago
八千年過ぎた頃から もっと恋しくなった
Since 8,000 years passed, I've missed you more
一億と二千年たっても 愛してる
I still love you even after 100,020,000 years
君を知ったその日から 僕の地獄に音楽は絶えない
Since the day I knew you, music has never ceased in my hell
幸せを願った だけど私の目に見えたのは
I wished for happiness, but what appeared before my eyes was
誰かの愛が違う 誰かの愛を殺す世界で
A world where someone's love kills another's love
この手に握った黒鉄 あとどれだけ理性を持っていられるのだろう
The black iron held in this hand, how much sanity can I keep?
それとも私は もう狂ってるの わからない
Or am I already losing my mind? I don't know
どんなに未来を描いて 望みもがいても届かない
No matter how much I draw the future, striving and struggling, I can't reach it
何が正しさと言いうの 誰が心まで裁くの
What do you call righteousness? Who even judges the heart?
ねえ 命が消える 優しさのせいで 弱さが罪と言うなら答えて
Hey, life disappears because of kindness. If weakness is a sin, answer me
私は誰を犠牲に生きていい? 銃口を向ける 間違わないように
Whose sacrifice am I allowed to live for? Aiming the muzzle so I won't make a mistake
唇を噛む 滲んだ血の味は 誰も同じ
Biting my lip, the taste of bleeding blood is the same for everyone
同じあなたと 奥に知っていた 終わりがない 悲しみの行く先は
You knew all along where the endless sorrow leads
どんなに怒りを飲み込み 消してもその火は燃え上がる
No matter how much anger I swallow and extinguish, that fire still burns up
見据えたまなざしの先は もう決してぶれたりしない
The destination of my fixed gaze will never waver again
響く 乾いた銃声 遠くで聞こえる 罵声と絶叫
Echoing dry gunshot, distant jeers and screams heard far away
正義を問いかける 私と彼ら どちらが死ねばいい
Questioning justice: Should I or they die?
守れるものは一つしかないから
Because there is only one thing I can protect
他人の痛みを想い
Thinking of others' pain,
心と寄り添う
drawing close to their hearts,
人はこんなにも美しいのに
people are so beautiful, yet
理由を見つけ 憎み合うんだね
they find reasons to hate each other.
生まれたcontaminated事に意味がなきゃいられないんだね
There must be a meaning to being born, right?
なら これが私の答えだから
Then this is my answer.
命が消える
Life disappears
優しさのせいで
because of kindness.
弱さが罪と言うなら答えて
If weakness is a sin, answer me.
私は誰を 犠牲に
Whose sacrifice
生きてい... 銃口を
should I live by? Aiming the gun
向けた あなたに見えるように
so that you can see,
そして銃声が 響く
and then a gunshot echoes.
遠くで聞こえる 罵声と
Distant jeers and screams
説教 正義を問いかける 私は生きる
questioning justice, I will live,
あなたを犠牲に 自らの
sacrificing you, choosing to
手を汚すことを 選んで
stain my own hands.
私は当事者になる 今
I become a party involved, now.
Hi IRyS! It's IRyS from Hololive English.
Thank you very much for coming to my very first 3D birthday live! Hope to the future, yay!
初めての、えーと、3Dバースデーライブへ来て下さりありがとうございます！
Thank you so much for coming to my very first 3D birthday live!
今回はね、えーと、「Hope to the Future」っていうタイトルのライブになっています。
This time, the live is titled "Hope to the Future."
And this time my live is based on a sci-fi anime song theme.
If you've noticed, my first two songs were Soukyuu no Fafner and Tōjisha, both from sci-fi anime.
えーと、今回のテーマはSFアニメーションになっています。先ほどの2曲もね、SFアニメーションになっているかなと思います。「蒼穹のファフナー」と「当事者」でした。
Um, the theme for this time is sci-fi anime. As you noticed, the first two songs were also from sci-fi anime: "Soukyuu no Fafner" and "Tōjisha."
And with this wonderful theme, we have this wonderful stage available.
Yes, that Steph-san made for me. Thank you so much! It is a sci-fi spaceship. We're in space, yes, this is the IRyS spaceship.
とっても素敵なね、えーと、SFテーマの、えーと、スペースシップ、宇宙船みたいな感じのステージになっています。
It's a really wonderful sci-fi themed spaceship-like stage.
And with this, I would like to say, please do tweet with the hashtag #IRySBDday while watching this to post your comments and what you think of this live during the stream. Yay!
And with this, I would like to say, please do tweet with the hashtag #IRySBDday while watching this to post your comments and thoughts about this live during the stream!
今回のハッシュタグ #IRySBDday でぜひ、えーと、このライブに関しての感想などありましたら、ぜひつぶやいてください！
Please share your thoughts and impressions of this live using the hashtag #IRySBDday!
Alrighty then, I think we should start off strong with a wonderful guest medley! では早速ね、えーと、ゲストメドレーに行きたいと思います！では、Let's go! どうぞ！
Alrighty then, I think we should start off strong with a wonderful guest medley! Let's go! Here we go!
御伽話は さっき死んだみたい
The fairy-tale seemed to have died just now,
煉瓦の病棟でうまく歌えなくて
in the brick hospital ward, unable to sing well.
霧に煙る夜浮かべる赤い月
On a night hazy in fog, a red moon floats.
ほらみて 私を 目を逸らしないで
Hey, look at me, don't avert your eyes.
黒い鉄格子の中で 私は生まれてきたんだ
In the black prison, I was born.
悪意の代償を願え 望むがままにお前に
Pray for the compensation of malice as you desire.
さあ与えよう正義を 壊して 壊される前に
Now I'll give you justice, break before you're broken.
因果の代償を払い 共に行こう 名前のない怪物
Paying the compensation of karma, let's go together, nameless monster.
耳鳴りがしている 鉄筋網うるさいって
There's a buzzing in my ears, the barbed wires are so noisy.
思い出せないの あの日の旋律
I can't remember the melody of those days.
雨はまだ止まない 何も見えないの
The rain won't stop yet, I can't see anything.
ほら見て こんなに大きくなったの
Look, it has grown so big.
黒い雨降らせこの空 私は望まれないもの
Bring black rain to this sky, I am undesired.
ひび割れたノイローゼ 愛す同罪の傍観者達に
My nervous breakdown is cracking, to the equally guilty onlookers I love.
さあ今振るわせ正義を 消せない傷を抱きしめて
Now, stir up that justice, embracing wounds that won't go away.
この身体を受け入れ 共に行こう
I'll accept this body and go together...
御伽話は さっき死んだみたい
The fairy tale seemed to have died just now,
煉瓦の病棟で うまく歌えなくて
In a brick hospital, unable to sing well,
霧に煙る夜 浮かべ赤い月
The foggy night brings up a red moon,
ほらみて 私を 目を逸らさないで
Look at me, don't look away.
耳鳴りがしてる 鉄条網うざさくて
A ringing in my ears, the barbed wire is so annoying,
思い出せないの あの日の旋律
I can't remember the melody of that day,
雨はまだ止まないの 何にも見えないの
The rain still hasn't stopped, I can't see anything,
ほら見て こんなに大きくなったの
Look, I've grown this big.
黒い雨降らせこの空 私は望まないもの
Black rain falling from this sky, I am something undesired,
ひび割れたノイローゼ 愛す同罪の傍観者達に
Cracked neurosis, to the bystanders sharing the same sin,
さあ今振るえ正義を 消せない傷を抱きしめて
Now tremble, justice, holding fast to unerasable scars,
この身体を受け入れ 共にゆこう 名前のない怪物
Accept this body and let's go together, nameless monster.
神ハ告ゲル 真ノ世界ヲ
God proclaims the true world.
黒い鉄格子の中で 私は生まれてきたんだよ
I was born inside these dark iron bars,
悪意の代償を願え 望むがままにお前に
Pray for the price of malice, as you wish,
さあ与えよう正義を 壊して 壊される前に
Now I'll grant you justice, before it breaks and is destroyed.
因果の代償を払い 共にゆこう 名前のない怪物
Pay the price of karma and let's go together, nameless monster.
神ハ告ゲル 真ノ世界ヲ
God proclaims the true world.
黒い鉄格子の中で 私は生まれてきたんだよ
I was born inside these dark iron bars,
悪意の代償を願え 望むがままにお前に
Pray for the price of malice, as you wish,
さあ与えよう正義を 壊して 壊される前に
Now I'll grant you justice, before it breaks and is destroyed.
黒い鉄格子の中で 私は生まれてきたんだよ
I was born inside these dark iron bars,
悪意の代償を願え 望むがままにお前に
Pray for the price of malice, as you wish,
さあ与えよう正義を 壊して 壊される前に
Now I'll grant you justice, before it breaks and is destroyed.
因果の代償を払い 報いよ 名前のない怪物
Pay the price of karma and be rewarded, nameless monster.
黒い雨降らせこの空 私は望まないもの
Black rain falling from this sky, I am something undesired,
ひび割れたノイローゼ 愛す同罪の傍観者達に
Cracked neurosis, to the bystanders sharing the same sin,
さあ今振るえ正義を 消せない傷を抱きしめて
Now tremble, justice, holding fast to unerasable scars,
この身体を受け入れ 共にゆこう 名前のない怪物
Accept this body and let's go together, nameless monster.
神ハ告ゲル 真ノ世界ヲ
God proclaims the true world.
我々! 寄席依れ!
Gather around, come together!
世界はDark!
The world is dark!
心くろくろ異形の神々
Dark hearts, grotesque deities,
私もあなたも恐がりなもの好き
Both you and I are curious cowards.
形むるむる異教徒逃げれば
If heretical believers run away,
私とあなたは大天下一でおデート
You and I will have a date under the blazing sun.
たのしいね 焼けるぞ溶けるぞ
It's so fun, burning and melting away,
骸ひやひや 其れでも好きです
Chilling skeletons, but I still love it.
私がいちばん 欲しいのは内緒よ
What I want most is a secret.
姿ぱやぱや 其れでは行きましょう
Fading figures, so let's go.
私にいちばん 似合うかな不条理
Is absurdity what suits me best?
鏡には うつらない
Not reflected in the mirror,
欲望は 言葉にしなくちゃ
Desires have to be put into words!
ほら 消えちゃうでしょ?
Look, they'll disappear, won't they?
太陽なんか 眩しくて
The sun is far too dazzling,
闇のほうが 無限で
The darkness is infinite.
太陽なんか眩しくって
The sun is so dazzling,
闇のほうが素敵
The darkness is much better!
CAOS CAOS I wanna CAOS
燃えよ混沌 無敵です
Burn, chaos! We're invincible!
CAOS CAOS うっせえなCAOS
CAOS CAOS Shut up, CAOS
燃えるような気持ち
A burning feeling...
世界はDark!
The world is Dark!
枕ぽかぽか無謀の神々
Fluffy-pillow thoughtless gods,
私とあなたと目的は違うの
You and I have different purposes.
絆むかむか無理矢理されがち
Forced to endure agonizing bonds,
私があなたを守るけどピンチ
I protect you, but we're in a pinch!
おかしいな 逃げるぞ 吠えるぞ
How strange, running and howling...
停まりおりおり ここまで来ました
Stopping from time to time, we've come this far.
私は黙って敵たちをケチラす
I silently brush the enemies aside.
蟠めらめら ここでは駄目です
Flames flickering, not here!
私にだまってスカウトしないで
Don't scout me in silence!
望むなら 全滅しましょうね
If you wish, let's annihilate them all!
願わくば 後形もなくね
Hopefully, leaving not even a trace!
あら いらないでしょ?
Oh, you don't need it, right?
現在なんと危険だった 光り物をください
It was so dangerous just now, give me something shiny!
現在なんと危険だった 光りもんで侵撃!
It was so dangerous just now, attack with shining things!
MADNESS MADNESS You wanna MADNESS
呼べば冒険 過激です
If you call, it's an extreme adventure!
MADNESS MADNESS ennui MADNESS
呼べばきっとおしまい
If you call, it's definitely the end!
太陽なんか眩しくって
The sun is so dazzling,
闇のほうが無限です
The darkness is infinite!
太陽なんか眩しくって
The sun is so dazzling,
闇のほうが素敵
The darkness is much better!
CAOS CAOS I wanna CAOS
燃えよ混沌 無敵です
Burn, chaos! We're invincible!
CAOS CAOS うっせえなCAOS
CAOS CAOS Shut up, CAOS
燃えるような気持ち
A burning feeling...
はいよるこんとんニャルラトホホ
Crawling chaos, Nyarlathotep!
聞こえていますか 僕の声が
Can you hear my voice?
大切な人は もういますか
Is there still someone precious to you?
遠いようで意外 とそばにいるよ
It seems far, but surprisingly I'm right beside you.
君には僕が見えないんだろうけど
You probably can't see me, but...
忘れないでなんて言えば 君は困るだろうから
If I say "don't forget," it'll trouble you, so...
忘れていいよなんて 最後まで強がった
I acted strong till the end, saying "it's okay to forget."
気付いてほしいよって 今さら伝えたら
If I told you now that I wanted you to notice,
やっぱり困った顔して笑うかな
Would you make that troubled face and smile?
今の日々を愛さないで そこには僕はいないんだよ
Don't cherish these present days, because I'm not there.
何気ないことが幸せだったって 当たり前でしょ
That casual moments were happiness—that's obvious, right?
もしもしも願い叶うのなら
If my wish could come true,
隣で笑ってくれるのなら
If you would smile right by my side,
愛を教えてくれた君とまたもう一度会いたい
I want to meet you once more, the one who taught me love.
もう一度 会いたい
I want to meet you once more.
歩き方も 話し方も
Your way of walking, your way of talking—
あの頃のままで 変わらないね
They're just like back then, unchanged.
でもなんだかちょっと
But somehow...
君の顔が
your face...
大人びて見えて
looks a bit more grown-up,
胸がきゅっと痛むよ
making my chest ache tightly.
別れが来ることを はじめから知っていたなら
If I had known from the start that parting would come,
おはよう ありがとう ごめんね おやすみを もっとちゃんと
I should have properly said good morning, thanks, sorry, and good night...
言えていたかなって 後悔しているよ
...I regret that I couldn't say them.
伝えたい言葉で溢れている
Overflowing with words I want to tell you,
今の君に触れてみたい
I want to touch you as you are now,
この手で強く抱き締めたい
and hold you tight with these hands.
君がいないこの世界から今日も名前を呼ぶよ
From this world without you, today too, I call your name.
まぶた閉じればいつもそこに 愛しい日々が蘇るよ
When I close my eyes, my beloved days always revive there.
涙色濡れた思い出さえも
Even memories soaked in tears
切なく煌めく
sparkle with sorrow.
空の色や街の音が 変わっても
Even if the sky's color and town's sounds change,
想いは消えずに残ってくんだね
these feelings remain without fading away.
だからせめてこの声が届いてほしいよ 君へ
So at least, I hope this voice reaches you...
今の日々を愛していて そこには僕はいないけれど
Please love the days you live now, even though I'm not there,
同じ時代を共に生きていたこと 忘れないでいて
and never forget that we lived through the same era together.
もしも生まれ変わるなら 僕らが笑い合えるのなら
If we were to be reborn, if we could smile together,
愛を教えてくれた君とまた もう一度巡り会いたい
I want to meet you once more, you who taught me what love is.
愛を教えてくれた君へ
To you, who taught me what love is.
この世界は非現実
This world is unreal,
ただ刷り込まれたビジョン
merely an implanted vision.
無限遠点 価値観を今 上書きする 変哲のない宇宙
Rewriting values at infinity now in an ordinary universe.
傲慢な神は 目に映らない 光速度で 支配し続けるなら
If an arrogant god, unseen to the eye, continues to rule at the speed of light,
僕は 僕だけは 奇跡的で 致命的な マイノリティ でいい
I, and I alone, am fine being a miraculous, fatal minority.
I can fly
あの瞬間、あの場面が キミにとって特別なら
If that moment and that scene were special to you,
過去は離れて 行くものなんかじゃなくて
the past isn't just something that drifts away,
傷付く事の痛みより 大事なシーン その全ての ヒカリが今ゼロを生む
instead of the pain of being hurt, the light of every precious scene gives birth to zero now.
I can fly high
この世界は非現実 ただ刷り込まれたビジョン
This world is unreal, just a scripted vision
無限遠点 価値観を 今 上書きする
Overwriting the value of infinity
この命という偶然 まだ錯覚とも知らず
This life called a coincidence, still not knowing it's an illusion
二律背反 パラドックスさえ 限らない世界線を欺き
Deceiving an endless worldline with antinomy and paradox
感情の支配 軌道秩序は
The rule of emotion, orbital order,
常識さえ 磨き上げていく
polishing even common sense.
ならば 彼の 彼のだけの 苦しみ
If so, my own, just my own suffering,
その欠陥さえ アルゴリズムのまま
even those flaws remain as algorithms.
I can fly high
愛の印 愛の言葉 明確なるこの記憶を
A sign of love, words of love, this clear memory
二度と彼方に 置き去りにはしないから
because I will never leave it behind in the distance.
いつでもまだ君の傍に 隣り合わせその両親が
Always still by your side, side by side, those two
もつれ合えば ゼロになる
if they entangle, it becomes zero.
There is no God, wonderful new world
まだ知らない 新しい空 世界線へと繋ぐのさ
Connecting to a new worldline, a sky we don't know yet
I can fly high
あの瞬間、あの場面が 君にとって特別 ならば
That moment, that scene, if it's special to you,
過去は離れていくもの なんかじゃなくて
the past isn't something that just drifts away.
傷つくことの痛みより 大事なシーン その全ての
Rather than the pain of hurt, the light of every scene
光が今 ゼロを生む
now gives birth to zero.
There is no God, wonderful new world
This place is worth visiting twice.
まだ知らない 新しい空 世界線へと繋ぐのさ
Connecting to a new worldline, a sky we don't know yet
I can fly high
あの瞬間、あの場面が 君にとって特別 ならば
That moment, that scene, if it's special to you,
過去は離れていくもの なんかじゃなくて
the past isn't something that just drifts away.
傷つくことの痛みより 大事なシーン その全ての
Rather than the pain of hurt, the light of every scene
光が今 ゼロを生む
now gives birth to zero.
There is no God, wonderful new world
握ったメッセージ that's rising hope
Clutched message, that's rising hope
揺るがない世界 非情な現状 続く壁は何重層?
An unshakeable world, a cruel reality, how many layers are the walls?
イメージ通りなんかないさ 静かに騒ぎ出した本能
Nothing like I imagined, my instincts quietly started to roar.
迷子みたい 行き止まりなんだもう思考はディストーション
Like a maze, a dead end, my thoughts are in distortion.
容赦ないね いつの間にか見失ったルート、暴れ出す
So unforgiving, the lost route starts to run wild.
Pay attention! Hey, what is it?
Watch your step now! 常識なんか要らない
Watch your step now! Common sense is not needed.
Are you serious!? No, no, no, don't worry 1, 2, 3
吹き返す心臓のリズム
The reviving rhythm of the heartbeat
視界 まだ眩んでる それでも行かなくちゃ
My vision is still dazzled, but I still have to go.
キミが信じてる ボクを裏切るわけにいかない
I can't betray the me you believe in.
強くクラクションが鳴る
The horn honks strongly.
孤独なまま時が経ったって 逃げる事覚えたって
Even if time passes in solitude, even if I learned to run away,
新しい今日が来ちまうけどう
a new tomorrow will come anyway.
この願い 喩え魔法が無くたって 叶えなくちゃ、誓った
This wish, even if magic doesn't exist, I swore I'd make it true.
ボクはこのキミと まだ見たい未来があるんだよ
I have a future I still want to see with you.
泣きそうでも 悔しくってさ 止まっていられない
Even if I look like I'm crying, I can't stop.
握ったメッセージ that's rising hope
Clutched message, that's rising hope
Demo, kedo, non-stop de gangan semaru hard way
Where's the solution!? 打ちのめされても
Where's the solution!? Even if I'm beaten down
Get up! Come on! And hurry up! Come on!
そんな損な時間なら すぐさまゴミ箱
Such wasteful time, straight into the trash can.
後悔なんて塵同様 さあ 2 step, ok shouting ok 欲張りをそそのかせ
Regrets are dust, come on 2 step, ok shouting ok, be greedy.
可否も賛否も全部ボクのもの 飛ばせ心臓のアルゴリズム
Approvals and disapprovals are mine, let the heart's algorithm fly.
ほら守りたいんだって ボクの声伝播した
Look, I wanted to protect it, my voice propagated.
異論反論は許すけど この想いは不用意に科学できないでしょ?
I'll allow objections, but can you carelessly science this feeling?
聞いてよ 辿り着いた正解 言わなくちゃいけない
Listen, the correct answer I arrived at, I have to say it.
キミがくれる想いの全部を信じていける
I can believe in all the feelings you give me.
それが嘘かどうかなんて わからなくてもいい
It doesn't matter if it's a lie or not.
誰かが示す見本ってなんだっけ 普通の愛ってなんだっけ
What was the example shown? What was normal love?
ボクは今日もボクに問いかける
I ask myself again today.
問いかける度手に入れるのは 変わらない真実
Every time I ask, what I get is an unchanging truth.
揺るがない世界 非情な現状
This world that isn't shaking, an abnormal situation,
続く壁は何重層?
how many layers are the walls?
イメージ通りなんかいやしない 静かに騒ぎだした本能
This isn't what I had in mind, my instincts quietly begin to stir.
吹き返す 心臓のリズム
The rhythm of my heart returns to life,
視界まだ眩んでいる
my vision is still blurry,
それでも行かなくちゃ
even so, I have to go.
キミが信じてる 僕を裏切るわけにいかない
I can't betray the you who trusts me.
強く クラクションが鳴る
The strong klaxon sounds,
孤独なままで時が経ったって
even if lonely days pass by,
誰かが示す見本ってなんだっけ
What is the example someone shows?
普通の愛ってなんだっけ
What is ordinary love?
ボクは今日もボクに問いかける
I keep asking myself today as well.
問いかけるたびに手に入れるのは 変わらない真実
Every time I ask, what I gain is an unchanging truth.
ボクはいらない まだ見たい未来があるから
I don't need it, because there's a future I still want to see.
孤独なんて 消えてなくなって
Even if loneliness disappears,
逃げる事 厭うなんて
even if I'm tired of running away,
新しい今日を探すんだよ
I'm searching for a new today.
この願い 例え魔法が無くたって 叶えなくちゃ誓った
Even if this wish must come true without magic, I vowed to fulfill it.
ボクとキミで創れる未来ならもう近い
If it's the future you and I create, it's already close.
ボクの右手 キミの左手 そっと繋いで
Softly connecting my right hand and your left hand,
握ったメッセージ that's rising hope
this message I held, that's rising hope.
離さないから that's rising hope
I won't let go, that's rising hope.
We will bring it rising hope!
Hey, can you continue, all right, make a way!
And I'm back. Hi IRyS, it's IRyS.
How'd you guys like Rising Hope? It was amazing, right?
Or more like, how did you guys enjoy the full guest medley? It was a whole medley!
I sang so many songs with so many of my wonderful JP senpais. Once again, thank you so much to my JP senpais...
And at the end, I really wanted to sing Rising Hope with everyone, so I'm really glad I was able to do that.
Thank you so much!
えっと、Rising Hope とあとゲストパートいかがでしたでしょうか。
Um, how did you like Rising Hope and the guest part?
えっとね、大変、あの光栄なことに、えっとJPの先輩にみんなにと一緒に、あのいろんな曲をね歌って、最後はね、あの豪華なキャストで Rising Hope 歌って
Um, it was such an honor to sing various songs together with all the JP senpais, and finally sing Rising Hope with a gorgeous cast.
本当にそれがね、あの1つ私の、なんていうの、あの目標っていうか願いだったんでね、それがその願いが叶えられてすごく嬉しいです。本当にありがとうございました！
That really was one of my goals, or rather my wish, so I'm so happy that wish came true. Thank you so much!
And I think we're at the halfway mark, yeah?
And now that we're in the halfway mark, we're also at a different place. ここはどこでしょうか? We are at the...
And now that we're in the halfway mark, we're also at a different place. Where are we? We are at the...
the say so church, yay!
Seiso Church, yay!
めちゃくちゃ清楚なチャ...あ、チャチャじゃない、教会にいます。
We're in a very seiso chu... ah, not chacha, church.
look at this pretty stained glasses, it's so pretty.
Look at this pretty stained glass, it's so pretty.
What kind of say so song is the say so Nephilim going to sing?
What kind of seiso song is the seiso Nephilim going to sing?
I do not know. No, I do know. I do know. But...
I wonder, I wonder. I'm sure you guys are wondering. Yes, この清楚な教会でね、この清楚なアイリスは一体どんな曲を歌うんでしょうか。でも楽しみですね。
I wonder, I wonder. I'm sure you guys are wondering. Yes, what kind of song will this seiso IRyS sing in this seiso church? But I'm looking forward to it.
では次の曲を聞いてください。Please listen to my next song.
Now please listen to my next song.
trust me trust you where is azure..
キラリ 一瞬の光 対極する 存在達よ さあ
A fleeting flash of light, to opposing beings, come now
土へ 未来へ
To the earth, to the future,
蒼穹へ
to the azure sky,
接近していく (一体何で?) 分かっている (理解なんて)
approaching step by step (Why on earth?) Understanding step by step (Understanding, huh?)
本当なら (悔やんで) そうあるべきだろう
If it were real (Regretting it) that's how it should be,
絶望なんて (消耗なんて) 宿命なんて (運命なんて)
despair (Exhaustion) fate (Destiny)
切り開いて (平常心で) 言い聞かせて
paving the way (With composure) Telling yourself,
そっと抱え込んでいく すっと通り過ぎていく 裏切り 揺らぎ 「dead or alive and go」
gently holding it all in, smoothly passing by, betrayal and wavering "dead or alive and go"
何処に行けば…世界と君が
Where should we go... so that the world and you
生命をやり直すために 「dead or alive and go」
can restart life "dead or alive and go"
生きていた証だ 記憶に刻め 向き合うのは…
It's proof that we lived, engrave it in your memories, heading to...
キラリ 一瞬の光 対極する 存在達よ
A fleeting flash of light, you polar opposites,
さあ 土へ 未来へ 蒼穹へ
now, heading toward earth, the future, the blue sky—
接近している
closing in.
(いったい何で？)
(What on earth is it?)
分かっている (理解なんて)
Understanding it... (understanding, you say?)
本当 なら (悔やんで) そうあるべきだろう
If it were true, (regretting it) it should be that way.
絶望なんて 消耗なんて 宿命なんて
Despair, consumption, destiny—
DEAD OR ALIVE AND GO
何処に行けば… 世界と君が 生命をやり直すために
Where should we go... so the world and you can restart life?
DEAD OR ALIVE AND GO
生きていた証だ 記憶に刻め 向かうは…
Proof that we lived, engraved in memory, heading toward...
痛い 痛い 痛い 砕け散っていく位
So painful, painful, painful, shattering to pieces—
cry cry 君と 蒼穹へ fly
cry cry flying toward the blue sky with you.
生き急いで (接近して)
Living in a rush, (closing in)
交錯して (分かって) 真実 に
intersecting, (understanding) toward the truth—
泣かないで 成長なんて (絶望なんて)
don't cry, growth, (despair)
飽和して (宿命) ディストレス の 抱擁
reaching saturation, (destiny) the embrace of distress—
そっと風になっていく
softly becoming the wind.
すっと心に生きづいて 花になる
Sinking smoothly into the heart to become a flower—
君と僕が 諦めぬまま 世界を巻き込んで行け
You and I, without giving up, keep swallowing up the world—
どうやって戦闘して 心読みあって 交わる
How do we fight, read each other's hearts, and cross paths?
輝く蒼穹は 僕らの鏡
The shining blue sky is our mirror,
今を映した azure
reflecting the present azure.
君とここに居る
I am here with you.
何処に行けば… 世界と君が 生命をやり直すために
Where should we go... so the world and you can restart life?
生きていた証だ 記憶に刻め 抗っていく
Proof that we lived, engraved in memory, fighting back—
君と僕が 諦めぬまま 世界を巻き込んで行け
You and I, without giving up, keep swallowing up the world—
どうやって戦闘して 心読みあって 交わる
How do we fight, read each other's hearts, and cross paths?
輝く空は 僕らの鏡 今を映した azure
The shining sky is our mirror, reflecting the present azure.
何処に行けば… 世界と君が 生命をやり直すために
Where should we go... so the world and you can restart life?
生きていた証だ 記憶に刻め 抗っていく
Proof that we lived, engraved in memory, fighting back—
君と僕が 諦めぬまま 世界を巻き込んで行け
You and I, without giving up, keep swallowing up the world—
どうやって戦闘して 心読みあって 交わる
How do we fight, read each other's hearts, and cross paths?
君とどこに居る 痛い 痛い 痛い 砕け散っていく位
Where I am with you... so painful, painful, painful, shattering to pieces—
cry cry 君と 蒼穹へ fly
cry cry flying toward the blue sky with you.
痛い 痛い 痛い 砕け散っていく位
So painful, painful, painful, shattering to pieces—
cry cry 君と 蒼穹へ fly
cry cry flying toward the blue sky with you.
And that was DEAD OR ALIVE. Yes, another beautiful song from the Fafner series.
Since I sang Shangri-La for my 3D showcase, I wanted to sing another Fafner song, so I chose DEAD OR ALIVE. How did you guys like that?
前回ね、あの3Dのお披露目配信ではシャングリラを歌ったので、それに続けて今回はDEAD OR ALIVEを歌わせていただきました。ファフナー最高なんで
In my previous 3D showcase, I sang "Shangri-La," so following that, this time I sang "DEAD OR ALIVE." Fafner is the best,
もし見てない方いらっしゃったら見てください。If you haven't watched Fafner yet, I highly recommend you do.
so if you haven't watched it yet, please do! If you haven't watched Fafner yet, I highly recommend you do.
And now that we sang DEAD OR ALIVE, I think we are past the halfway halfway line of this live.
And now that we've sung "DEAD OR ALIVE," I think we are past the halfway mark of this live.
And now since that's the case, I think it's about time we... And now it's something big, something that I think a lot of you guys were completely expecting
And since that's the case, I think it's about time we... Now, for something big—something I think many of you were completely expecting
because it's, you know, it's the usual stuff. では、えっと告知タイムに行きましょうか。
because, you know, it's the usual stuff. Now then, let's move on to announcement time!
みんさんがおらふく期待していたていうか、まあいつものね、告知させていただきます。では、どん！
Everyone has probably been expecting it—well, the usual announcement. Here it is!
So, I will be releasing my birthday merch this year.
As you can see, it is sci-fi themed just like the live, yay!
In with IRyS in her...
Featuring IRyS in her...
と 今回 は ね 、 え と 今回 の ライブ に 合わせ て SF テーマ の イラスト に なっ て い ます 。
And this time, it's matched with the live concert, featuring a sci-fi themed illustration.
えー と 、 で は 詳細 行き ましょう か 。 Now let's go to the details, yay!
Let's go into the details, yay!
First off, we have the "Hope To The Future" DeskMatRyS, yay!
えーと 、 ラバ マ と ワイド デスク マット に なっ て い ます 。
Um, it's a rubber-matted wide desk mat.
From the same art from pippo-sensei, it is slightly larger or wider than my past birthday mat
From the same art by pippo-sensei, it is slightly larger or wider than my past birthday mat
that I released a couple years ago, so I think you'll definitely have a need for that.
It is going to look very nice on your desk.
えー と 、 今回 の デスク マット は ね 、 えー と 、 何 年 か 前 に 、 の 誕生日 に リリース し た デスク マット より ちょい と 長く なっ て い ます 。
Um, this desk mat is a bit longer than the one I released a few years ago for my birthday.
なので ぜひ ぜひ 、 あの 、 デスク に 広げ て いただける と 多分 この イラスト とても デスク の 上 で 映える と 思う んで 、 ぜひ ゲット し て ください 。
So please spread it out on your desk, I think this illustration will really pop on your desk, so please definitely get it.
今回 の ね 、 あの 、 イラスト 自体 は ね 、 あの 、 本当 に SF な の で 、 パソコン 周り と か 全然 似合う ん じゃ ない か な と 思い ます 。 Alrighty then,
The illustration itself is truly sci-fi, so I think it will look great around your PC setup! Alrighty then,
next merch, 次 いき ましょう 。
next merch, let's move on.
The Gamer JacketRyS (Jacket), yay! The hypothetical jacket is no longer hypothetical! Yay!
えー と 、 今回 の 、 えー と 、 衣装 、 衣装 じゃ ない 、 えー と 、 ゲーマー 衣装 の 、 えー と 、 再現 の ジャケット に なっ て い ます 。
Um, this time, um, outfit—not outfit, um, it's a reproduction jacket of the gamer outfit.
えー と 、 今回 は ね 、 再現 と 言っ て も 、 あの 色違い に なっ て い ます 。 みんな が 使い やすい よう な 黒 に さ せ て いただき まし た 。 でも デザイン 自体 は 、 えー と 、 おそろい の デザイン に なっ て い ます 。 多分 とっても かっこいい の で ぜひ ゲット し て ください 。
Um, this time, even though we call it a reproduction, it's in a different color. We made it black so it's easy for everyone to use. But the design itself is a matching design. It's probably super cool, so please definitely get it.
And as I mentioned before, I think maybe in a past stream that I wanted to release a jacket, matching jacket, yay!
And as I mentioned before, I think maybe in a past stream that I wanted to release a matching jacket, yay!
It is in a different color, it is in black so that it will be easier for all of you guys to wear, but the design is going to be matching with my outfit
It is in black so that it will be easier for all of you guys to wear, but the design is going to be matching with my outfit
my gamer outfit, so I think it'd be nice to be matching, yay! えー と 、 今回 の ね 、 おそろい な ので 、 ぜひ ご 購入 お 願い し ます 。
my gamer outfit, so I think it'd be nice to be matching, yay! Um, this time it's matching, so please purchase it.
Okay, and then next up, we have more clothes, まだ 、 えー と 、 お 洋服 系 の 、 えー と 、 グッズ あり ます よ 。
Okay, and then next up, we have more clothes, we still have some apparel-related merch, you know.
The GuyRyS Cap, woo!
Finally, I'm sure a lot of you guys wanted a GuyRyS cap for the longest time ever since GuyRyS came to existence.
It is a white cap with the GuyRyS logo on it. Yes, it has your face on it, and it is white because, you know, GuyRyS cap has to be white. It is going to look amazing with the jacket, so I think it is—it'd be best to buy it as a set. Yes.
It is a white cap with the GuyRyS logo on it. Yes, it has your face on it, and it is white because, you know, GuyRyS cap has to be white. It is going to look amazing with the jacket, so I think it'd be best to buy it as a set. Yes.
今回 の ね 、 えー と 、 IRyS の 、 あの 、 ファン 、 ファン そう の ガイリス の 帽子 に なっ て い ます 。 ボリリス 帽子 を 再現 し まし た 。 帽子 は ね 、 あの 、 ガイリス の 、 あの 、 キャラクター で も 白い 帽子 かぶっ て ん で 、 その 白い 帽子 に なっ て い ます 。 それ で ガイリス の 顔 が 映っ てる 帽子 に なっ て い ます 。 あの ね 、 ガイリス 、 IRyS の リスナー さん だっ たら 、 この 帽子 かぶん ない と だめ でしょ ? ご 購入 し て ちょうだい ?
Um, this time, it's the GuyRyS hat, the fan-favorite GuyRyS hat. We reproduced the Bori-RyS hat. The hat is white, just like the character GuyRyS wears, and it has GuyRyS's face on it. You know, if you're an IRyS listener, you have to wear this hat, right? Please go buy it!
あと 、 えー と 、 ジャケット と ね 、 あの 黒い ジャケット と 、 たぶん いい 色 の コントラスト に なる と 思う ん で 、 ぜひ 一緒 に 買っ て 一緒 に 着用 し て ください 。 Yay!
Also, with the jacket, the black jacket, it'll probably have a nice color contrast, so please buy them together and wear them together. Yay!
If you buy the full set, we have a bonus postcard, yay!
As for the postcards this time, there will be a limited edition set, and of course if you can't get the limited edition set, there will be of course the normal set bonus as well, so no worries. For the limited edition set, there will be the postcard with the Iris handwritten, hand-signed, hand-signed, I will sign them one by one, postcards, yay!
As for the postcards this time, there will be a limited edition set, and of course if you can't get the limited edition set, there will be of course the normal set bonus as well, so no worries. For the limited edition set, there will be the postcard with the IRyS handwritten, hand-signed, hand-signed, I will sign them one by one, postcards, yay!
えー 、 そう 、 if you want the hand-signed postcard, please do hurry and get it. Yay, buy it, buy it now, yay!
Um, so, if you want the hand-signed postcard, please do hurry and get it. Yay, buy it, buy it now, yay!
And if you perhaps do not make it for the limited edition set, no worries, there's still the normal, um, stacked IRyS, uh, postcard with the hand, with the signature...
Complete Set Purchase Bonus = Illustration: び助 Please look forward to the special message from IRyS! Yes.
Complete Set Purchase Bonus = Illustration: Bisuke. Please look forward to the special message from IRyS! Yes.
えーっと 今回のね、セット特典のポストカードになっていまーす。
Um, for this time's set purchase bonus, it's a postcard!
えーっと 今回も前回と同じく、えーっと 限定 数量限定バージョンと通常セットも両方ともあります。
And just like last time, there's both a quantity-limited version and a regular set.
数量限定の方ではアイリスの、あの 直筆サインを1枚1枚大切に書かせていただきますんで、えーっと、それ希望の方はぜひ早めにご購入をお願いします！
For the limited one, I'll write my handwritten signature carefully on each, so please buy early!
えーっと、通常セットもぜひあるんで、えーっと、期間、期間限定じゃなくて数量限定のがもしなくなった場合はぜひぜひ通常限定は、よろしくお願いします！通常限定じゃない、通常のほうはよろしくお願いします！
There's also a regular set, so if the limited one sells out, please get the regular version!
そちらの方でもアイリスのね、あの 多分汚い字ではなく綺麗なアイリスの、あの 箔押し、えーっと サインとメッセージがついていますんで是非そちらもゲットしてください！
That version also includes my foil-stamped signature and message, so please get that too!
イエーイ！
Yay!
あー That was the merch announcement! どぅ、how do you guys like the merch? I honestly really really like the merch this time.
Ah, that was the merch announcement! How do you guys like the merch? I really like it this time.
うん 今回の、あの グッズどうでしたか？すごく今回のグッズすごく楽し みっていうか、めっちゃ、めちゃくちゃ出来いいんじゃないかなっていう風に思ってるんでぜひゲットしてください！
Yeah, I think they turned out super well, so I hope you'll check them out!
えーっと、And not just that, there's still one more announcement まだね、もう一つこちらあります。
And not just that, there's still one more announcement. There's one more right here!
なんと！I will be having a members-only after birthday stream, right after this! イエーイ！It is a special stream to thank my members.
What's more! I will be having a members-only after birthday stream right after this! Yay!
I will be singing more songs there. So if you want to hear more IRyS singing after the stream,
どぅ、join my membership, myのファミリー、and be there. And I hope you be there.
do join my membership, my NeoFamily, and I hope you'll be there.
はい、えーっと 今回はなんと初めてのね、あの 誕生日記念配信のあとの、えーっと 面限 配信をやります！そちらの方でもねアイリス歌うんで、こちらの配信でね、えーっと、も、もう少しアイリスの曲、アイリスの歌聴きたいなっていう、気分になった方はぜひぜひ、えーっとアイリスのメンバーシップに
I'll be doing my first members-only stream right after the birthday stream! I'll be singing there too.
加入していただくと、そのすぐあとに、えーっと メンバー限定配信のアクセスできるんでぜひ加入して、見に来てくださいね！
If you join, you'll immediately get access to the members-only stream, so please come check it out!
ふー でわ、でわでわ、えーっと now that I have announced my merch,
Well then, now that I've announced my merch,
I think we're getting towards the last part, but there's still more singing obviously. And since we're singing more songs, I think we need to move back to the arena, the SF arena. Yeah.
we're getting towards the last part, but there's still more singing. We need to move back to the arena.
えーっと、まだ曲歌いますけど、そろそろ、あの 最後の方になってきましたんで、えーっと 次の曲はね、えーっと またアリーナの方に戻りたいなと思っています。
Since we're nearing the end, for the next song, I'd like to head back to the arena.
では行きましょう！Let's go! イエーイ！
Let's go! Yay!
花なら 散りゆく
If they are flowers, they scatter away
夢なら 果てなく
If they are dreams, they have no end
それなら 魂は
If so, where do our souls return to?
何処へと 還らん
Where do they return to?
仕組み まれている 終結さえも
Even the prearranged endings,
求め過ぎてた 答えならば
we sought too much for answers.
記号の中で 泳ぎ疲れて
Swimming tiredly within symbols,
行き着く先は ただの「カリソメ」
where we arrive is just a temporary "karisome".
永い とき はなれても
Even separated for a long time,
知っている 必ず 呼び合う
I know, we will always call out to each other.
絆を 運命 と呼ぶこと 抱いて 抱きしめても
Calling bonds our destiny, embracing and holding tight,
抜け出せない 定められた さかいから
yet unable to escape from the ordained boundary.
溶けてなくなるほどの 進化へと おかえりなさい
Melting toward an evolution that vanishes—welcome back.
白い結晶が ふりそそぐ都市
White crystals fall upon the city,
全ては包まれるだけ
everything is just enveloped.
誰が決めた訳でもない夢へ おかえりなさい 心のままに
Toward a dream no one decided upon—welcome back, follow your heart.
君の瞳に 映るその自分 何を想って 何を見てる
The self reflected in your eyes, what are you thinking, what are you seeing?
感じる事に 信じる事に ゆだねる事に
About feeling, about believing, about surrendering...
臆病になる
turning cowardly.
永い 時 待っていた
I've been waiting for a long time.
微笑んで 支えになりましょう
Let's smile and be each other's support.
ひとり で 空 に 願 う の な ら
If you're wishing upon the sky alone,
いつか 繰り返す 命の出口
someday, at the exit of repeating lives,
さらに その先の 道も
even the path beyond that...
きっと 出会えると 信じて泣こう
let's cry, believing we'll surely meet.
おやすみなさい
Good night.
赤い 悲しみが 渦巻く波間
Between the waves where red sorrow swirls,
寄せては返す いとなみ
the tide approaches and recedes.
愛し 愛され 一つになるまで おやすみなさい
Loving and being loved until we become one, good night.
時は満ちるから
For the time has come.
永い 時 離れても 知っている
Even if we are apart for a long time, I know
必ず 呼び合う 絆を
the bond that will always call out to us
運命と呼ぶこと
is what we call destiny.
抱いて 抱きしめても 抜け出せない
Embracing, even if I hold you tight, I can't escape
定められた 境から
from the predetermined boundary.
溶けてなくなる ほどの進化へと
Toward an evolution so deep it melts away,
おかえりなさい
welcome back.
白い やさしさが ふりそそぐ街 全ては包まれるだけ
White kindness pours down on the town, enveloping everything.
誰が 決めた わけでもない夢へ
Toward a dream that nobody decided on,
おかえりなさい
welcome back.
心のままに
as your heart desires.
メデタシ ソワレ
Happily ever after, soiree.
アンコール アンコール アンコール アンコール
Encore! Encore! Encore! Encore!
I just used up all my energy and broken to pieces, though.
I just used up all my energy and broke into pieces, though.
どうしよっかな～ しょうがないな～
What should I do? Oh well.
あとね、メルシーセールが10時5分から始まるよ！
Merch sale starts at 10:05 and my membership part at 10:15!
では最後の曲、ガーネットを聴いてください。
Please listen to my last song, Garnet.
グラウンド 駆けっていく あなたの背中は
Running across the field, your back
空に 浮かんだ 雲 よりも 自由で
was freer than the clouds floating in the sky.
ノートに 並んだ 四角い文字さえ
Even the square letters lined up in my notebook
すべてを照らす 光 に見えた
seemed like a light illuminating everything.
好きという気持ちが 分からなくて
Not understanding the feeling called love,
二度とは戻らない この時間が
this time that will never return
その意味をあたしに 教えてくれた
taught me its true meaning.
あなたと過ごした 日々を この胸に焼き付けよう
I'll burn the days I spent with you into this chest.
思い出さなくても 大丈夫なように
So that I'll be fine even without remembering,
いつか他の誰かを 好きになったとしても
even if I someday come to love someone else.
ずっと特別で
Always special,
大切で またこの季節がめぐってく
And so precious, another season comes around.
またこの季節がめぐってく
Once again, another season comes around.
...
ずっと 特別で 大切で
Always special, and so precious.
またこの季節がやってくる
Again, this season comes around.
...
ずっと 特別で 大切で
Always special, and so precious.
またこの季節がめぐってく
Again, this season comes around.
Thank you so much guys for coming to my very first 3D birthday live!
I've always wanted to do this, so I'm super happy that I was able to finally do this.
And thank you so much for all your support and all the wonderful staff that were involved in making this live possible...
and making this amazing.
Thank you so much!
あの、たくさんみんな初めての3Dライブに来てくださり、ありがとうございました！
えっと、みんなの応援のおかげ、それと素敵なスタッフさんのあの努力のおかげで、とてもいいライブになったかなと思います。
本当にありがとうございました！
そして、チャンネル登録100万人も本当にありがとうございます！
みんなのおかげです。
And thank you so much for helping me reach 1 million subscribers today. I really appreciate it.
Thank you very much for coming, IRyS!
Bye-bye, IRyS!
IRyS'S BIRTHDAY LIVE 2024 HOPE TO THE FUTURE